Gould, Samuel; Papers apap058
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Reports and Published and Unpublished Works, 1936-1980; Undated; 3; 0.81 cubic ft.
  - "University Television Comes of Age," Correspondence and Drafts for New York Times, 1966 (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 136)
  - "Toward Full Maturity," Report of the Chancellor, SUNY, 1966-1967 (Box 3 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 137)
  - Articles Published by Gould and Accompanying Correspondence, 1966-1967; Undated (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 1)
  - "The Modern University: Concerns for the Future,"Science Magazine, 1967 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 2)
  - "Progress and Reappraisal," Report of the Chancellor, SUNY, 1967-1968 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 3)
  - "The Emerging Role of Management in Higher Education," Manuscript and Correspondence, ca. 1968 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 4-5)
  - "Creation of the Future: Properties of Growth and Change," SUNY Master Plan Revised, 1968 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 6)
  - "Into the Third Decade," Annual Report of the Chancellor, SUNY, 1968-1969 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 7)
  - "Continuing Education in State University: Obligations and Responsibilities" Prepared from a Speech for Printing in Continuing Education, and Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 8)
  - "The Intellectual Role of the University in Our Society," Correspondence and Writing for Encyclopedia of Education, with the Macmillan Company, 1968-1969 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 9)
  - "Public Universities and the Future," Correspondence and Article for New York Times, 1969 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 10)
  - "The New Social Role of Graduate Education," Correspondence and Writing for The Graduate Journal, 1969-1970 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 11)
  - "The Second Plateau," Annual Report of the Chancellor, SUNY, Introductory Section, 1969-1970 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 12)
  - Today's Academic Condition, Correspondence on Book's Publishing with McGraw Hill, 1970 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 13)
  - "Perils and Promise of College for All,"New York Times Article, 1970 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 14)
  - "Chancellor's Panel on University Purposes: Background Paper on the Arts, Society and Education," by Gibson A. Danes, Dean of Visual Arts, SUNY at Purchase, Staff Member of the Chancellor's Panel on University Purposes, 1970 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 15)
  - "The Growing Assault on Reason," Published in Monitor with Correspondence, 1970 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 16)
  - Correspondence and Book Review of Any Person, Any Study, by Sir Eric Ashby, 1971 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 17)
  - Review of "The Capitol and the Campus: State Responsibility for Postsecondary Education," Correspondence and Review, 1971 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 18)
  - "The Prospects for Non-Traditional Study," Article for Science Education News, 1972 (Box 4 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 19)
  - "Diversity By Design," Abstract of Major Findings and Recommendations, Commission on Non-Traditional Studies Final Report, 1973 (Box 5 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 1)
  - "Toward a Society of Life Long Learners," Prepared for American Association of University Women Journal Magazine, 1973 (Box 5 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 2)
  - "Changing Patterns in Higher Education," Manuscript and Correspondence, 1974 (Box 5 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 3)
  - Higher Education in the Year 2000: Still Another Look Into the Future," Article for Change Magazine, 1975 (Box 5 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 4)
  - "Independent Learning and the Future Role of Libraries," Prepared for the American Library Association Yearbook, 1975 (Box 5 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 5)
  - Gould Interview at the College of DuPage, IL, Transcript and Correspondence, 1980 (Box 5 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 6)
  - A Maverick in the Establishment by Samuel Gould, Undated (Box 5 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 7)
  - A Maverick in the Establishment Part 1, by Samuel Gould, Undated (Box 5 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 8)
  - A Maverick in the Establishment Part 2, by Samuel Gould, Undated (Box 5 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 9)
  - A Maverick in the Establishment Part 3, by Samuel Gould, Undated (Box 5 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 10)
  - The Primrose Sphinx, Undated (Box 5 (3-Reports and Published and Unpublished Works), Folder 11)
- Administrative Files, 1964-1989; Undated; 4; 0.11 cubic ft.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  This series contains administrative records, such as memorandums and press releases. It also includes correspondence between Gould and Rockefeller.
  - Memos to Chief Administrative Officers, 1964-1966 (Box 5 (4-Administrative Files), Folder 12)
  - Press Releases Involving Gould, 1964-1970; 1977 (Box 5 (4-Administrative Files), Folder 13)
  - Correspondence between Gould, Rockefeller, and Mrs. Moore, 1964-1966; 1970 (Box 5 (4-Administrative Files), Folder 14)
  - Fifth Annual SUNY Convention, Address and Materials, 1980; Undated (Box 5 (4-Administrative Files), Folder 15)
  - New York State Dinner honoring Apollo 8 Crew Program, 1989 (Box 5 (4-Administrative Files), Folder 16)
  - Antioch College Photographs, Undated (Box 5 (4-Administrative Files), Folder 17)
  - Drawings Given to Gould of Unidentified Buildings, Undated (Box 5 (4-Administrative Files), Folder 18)